Ann Cottrell Free Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1904-2007 (Box 51-223)
  - Lancaster, Clay, 1984 (Box 146)
  - Land and ranges, 1966-1977, (2 folders) (Box 146)
  - Latham Foundation, 1981-1989 (Box 146)
  - Latvia, 1946-1948 (Box 146)
  - Lemke, Antje B., 1977-1989 (Box 146)
  - Life Conservation Association, Taiwan, 1994-1997 (Box 146)
  - Lindgren, Astrid, 1988-1989 (Box 146)
  - Lions, 1965-1966 (Box 146)
  - Livestock, 1959-1991, (6 folders) (Box 147)
  - Livestock, 1959-1991, (2 folders) (Box 148)
  - Magel, Charles, 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 148)
  - Malayan Problems by Cheng Lock Tan, 1947 (Box 148)
  - Malta, 1984 (Box 148)
  - March for Animals, Washington, D.C., 1990, June 10 (Box 148)
  - March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, Washington, D.C., 1963 (Box 148)
  - Marine mammals, 1971-1987, (2 folders) (Box 149)
  - Marshall Plan (Box 149)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1948-1949 (Box 149)
    - "History of George Catlett Marshall," undated, (2 folders) (Box 149)
    - Miscellany, 1948-1949, 1987 (Box 149)
    - Notebooks, circa 1948-1949 (Box 149)
  - Massachusetts Society for the Protection of Animals, 1963-1990 (Box 149)
  - McCarthy, Colman, 1988-1995 (Box 150)
  - McClintock, Barbara, 1983 (Box 150)
  - Mental health; Brain, 1972-1990 (Box 150)
  - "Miss Waldron's monkey," 2007 (Box 150)
  - Mississippi Animal Rescue League, 1972-1990, (3 folders) (Box 150)
  - Montfort of Colorado, 1974-1979 (Box 150)
  - Montgomery County Humane Society, Md. (Box 151)
    - Animal shelter, 1951, 1963-1975 See also OV 5, same heading, (5 folders) (Box 151)
    - Bills and legislation, 1955, 1967-1974, (2 folders) (Box 151)
    - Miscellany, 1961-1998, undated, (7 folders) (Box 152)
    - Reorganization, 1972-1974 (Box 153)
  - Morocco, 1978-2002, (2 folders) (Box 153)
  - Moses, Lucille, 1961-1991 (Box 153)
  - National Alliance for Animal Legislation, 1985-1991, (2 folders) (Box 153)
  - National Alliance for Animals, 1988-1995 (Box 153)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1966-1991 (Box 153)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1966-1991 (Box 154)
  - National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 1947-1951, 1979-2001 See also Containers 211-213, Washington Press Club (Box 154)
  - National Resources Defense Council, 1975-1979 (Box 154)
  - National Society for Medical Research, 1950-1998, (4 folders) (Box 154)
  - National Zoological Park, Washington, D.C., deer hunting, 1977-1983, (5 folders) (Box 155)
  - New England Anti-Vivisection Society, 1989-2001 (Box 155)
  - New Forest Society for the Prevention of Straying Animals, 1963-1966 (Box 156)
  - News organizations, contacts, 1961, undated (Box 156)
  - Obituaries, 1948-2005, (5 folders) (Box 156)
  - Œuvre d'assistance aux bêtes d'abattoirs, 1973-1994 (Box 156)
  - Œuvre d'assistance aux bêtes d'abattoirs, 1973-1994 (Box 157)
  - Operation Outreach-USA, 1991-1992 (Box 157)
  - Patterson, Mary Marvin Breckinridge, 1982-1987 (Box 157)
  - Pennsylvania Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, 1971-1975 (Box 157)
  - People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA), 1981-1996, (4 folders) (Box 157)
  - People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals; Newkirk, Ingrid, 1974-2003 (Box 158)
  - Pesticides (Box 158)
    - Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), 1959-1975, (2 folders) (Box 158)
    - Insects, 1958-1976, (3 folders) (Box 158)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1995 (Box 158)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1995, (6 folders) (Box 159)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1995 (Box 160)
  - Pet Gazette; Senior, Faith A., 1987-1989 (Box 160)
  - Pets (Box 160)
    - Miscellany, 1957-2002, (4 folders) (Box 160)
    - Miscellany, 1957-2002, (6 folders) (Box 161)
    - Overpopulation, 1971-1993, (5 folders) (Box 162)
    - Therapy, 1961-1980 (Box 162)
    - Therapy, 1961-1980 (Box 163)
  - Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine, 1986-1992 (Box 163)
  - Pigs, 1963-2001, (5 folders) (Box 163)
  - Pigs, 1963-2001, (7 folders) (Box 164)
  - Pigs, 1963-2001, (2 folders) (Box 165)
  - Plants and botany, 1973-1990 (Box 165)
  - Poetry Therapy Institute, 1975-1976 (Box 165)
  - Polk, George, 1938-1940, 1989, undated (Box 165)
  - Poplar Springs Animal Sanctuary, Poolesville, Md., 1970-2002 (Box 165)
  - Potomac Valley Conservation and Recreation Council, 1957-1972 (Box 166)
  - Poultry, 1957-2003, (7 folders) (Box 166)
  - Poultry, 1957-2003, (6 folders) (Box 167)
  - Poultry, 1957-2003, (5 folders) (Box 168)
  - Predators and predator control, 1955-1972 (Box 168)
  - Primates, 1959-2001, (6 folders) (Box 169)
  - Primates, 1959-2001, (5 folders) (Box 170)
  - Progressive Animal Welfare Society, 1983-1994 (Box 170)
  - Psychologists for the Ethical Treatment of Animals; Summit for the Animals, Arlington, Va. (1990, Mar. 10-11), 1989-1997 (Box 171)
  - Rabbits, 1960-1993, (2 folders) (Box 171)
  - Rachael's Women's Center, Washington, D.C., 1980-1981 (Box 171)
  - Racoons, 1959-1970 (Box 171)
  - Rats and mice, 1959-2000, (2 folders) (Box 171)
  - Regenstein, Lewis, 1978-1979 (Box 171)
  - Rodeos and bullfighting, 1962-1992 See also OV 5, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 172)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 172)
    - Anderson, Marian, 1939-1991 (Box 172)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1941-1984, (5 folders) (Box 172)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1941-1984, (4 folders) (Box 173)
    - Articles and writings by others, 1933-1982, (3 folders) (Box 173)
    - Articles and writings by others, 1933-1982, (3 folders) (Box 174)
    - Biographical material, 1962-1963, undated (Box 174)
    - Black, Ruby A. (Box 174)
      - Correspondence, 1933-1957 (Box 174)
      - Miscellany, 1925-1958, undated, (2 folders) (Box 174)
      - Motheral, Cornelia J., 1961-1965, 1982 (Box 174)
      - National Youth Administration, 1934-1945 (Box 174)
      - Press, 1933-1942 (Box 174)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor, views, 1933-1944 (Box 175)
      - "This War" press conference, 1937-1946, (3 folders) (Box 175)
      - United Nations, 1945-1946 (Box 175)
      - Universal training, 1944-1945 (Box 175)
      - "Unusual visitors," 1933-1938 (Box 175)
      - Veterans, 1944-1946 (Box 175)
      - White House, 1927-1945, (2 folders) (Box 175)
      - White House, 1931-1946, (7 folders) (Box 176)
      - Working women, 1932-1946 (Box 176)
      - Works Progress Administration, 1933-1942, (2 folders) (Box 177)
    - Civil rights, 1937, 1944 (Box 177)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1948, 1982-1986, undated (Box 177)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt centennial, 1984, (4 folders) (Box 177)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Encyclopedia, 1982-2004, undated, (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - Helm, Edith, 1952-1962 (Box 178)
    - "If You Ask Me" column, Ladies Home Journal, 1941-1945 (Box 178)
    - Miscellany, circa 1933-2011, undated, (4 folders) (Box 178)
    - Miscellany, circa 1933-2011, undated (Box 179)
    - Mrs. Roosevelt's Press Conference Association, 1940-1945, 1980-1999, undated, (2 folders) (Box 179)
    - "My Day" column, 1937-1953 (Box 179)
    - Photographs, circa 1934-1948, 1962 (Box 179)
    - "Press girls"; "News women," 1933-1987, 1999, (6 folders) (Box 179)
    - "Press girls"; "News women," 1944-1963, 1970, 1979-1984, 1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 180)
    - Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1947, 1998 (Box 180)
    - Val-Kill, Hyde Park, N.Y., 1980-2004, undated (Box 180)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1937-1997, (4 folders) (Box 180)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1937-1997, (2 folders) (Box 181)
  - Royal Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, 1963-1981, (3 folders) (Box 181)
  - Rural America, 1975-1978 (Box 181)
  - Russia, 1943-1984 See also CL 1, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 181)
  - Schweitzer, Albert (Box 181)
    - Albert Schweitzer Center, Barrington, Mass., 1975-1994 (Box 181)
    - Albert Schweitzer Council on Animals and the Environment, 1989-1990 (Box 182)
    - Albert Schweitzer Fellowship (Box 182)
      - Alumni Newsletter, 1997-1998 (Box 182)
      - Board of directors, 1974-1987, (7 folders) (Box 182)
      - Board of directors, 1988-1995, (6 folders) (Box 183)
      - By laws and mission statement, 1979-1988 (Box 183)
      - Courier, 1974-1996, (2 folders) (Box 184)
      - Marshall, George, 1948, 1975-1993 (Box 184)
      - Medical fellows program, 1980-1992, (2 folders) (Box 184)
      - Photographs, 1988, undated (Box 184)
      - Reverence, 1981-2002 (Box 185)
      - Summer fellowships, Catholic University of America, Washington, D.C., 1983-1989, undated, (7 folders) (Box 185)
      - Urban fellows program, 1992-1996 (Box 186)
    - Albert Schweitzer Institute for the Humanities, Quinnipiac College, Hamden, Conn., 1990-1999, (2 folders) (Box 186)
    - Albert Schweitzer Memorial Foundation, 1984-1990 (Box 186)
    - "Albert Schweitzer's Thought and Its Relationship to the Contemporary Scene," Wingspread, Racine, Wis., 1977, Oct. 21-23, (2 folders) (Box 186)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1963-1993, (2 folders) (Box 186)
    - Articles and writings by others, 1956-2002, (3 folders) (Box 187)
    - Centenary, 1974-1976 (Box 187)
    - Correspondence (Box 187)
      - Incoming, 1952-1999, (2 folders) (Box 187)
      - Outgoing, 1964-2000 (Box 187)
    - Death, 1965 (Box 187)
    - Eerbied voor het Leven (publication), 1983-1986 (Box 188)
    - Gabon; Godofredo, Stutzin, 1972-1989 (Box 188)
    - "Guide to Albert Schweitzer Collections in the United States," 1981 (Box 188)
    - Hôpital Albert Schweitzer, Lambaréné, Gabon; Association International de l'oeuvre du Docteur Albert Schweitzer de Lambaréné, 1973-2000, (3 folders) (Box 188)
    - Hôpital Albert Schweitzer, Lambaréné, Gabon; Association International de l'oeuvre du Docteur Albert Schweitzer de Lambaréné, 1973-2000 See also OV 2, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 189)
    - Miller, Rena Schweitzer, 1977, 1990-2004 (Box 189)
    - Miscellany, 1961-2002, (3 folders) (Box 189)
    - Music, 1975-1995, (2 folders) (Box 190)
    - Nies-Berger, Edouard, 1986-2002, (4 folders) (Box 190)
    - "'Reverence for Life': The Ethical Mysticism of Albert Schweitzer" by Ara Paul Barsam, 1998 (Box 190)
    - Stockwell, John, 1989-1990 (Box 191)
    - Symposia and conferences, 1978-1983, 1990-1992, 2000 (Box 191)
    - Wiebers, David O., 1991-1992 (Box 191)
    - "Words of Schweitzer," 1957-1992 (Box 191)
  - Scientists Center for Animal Welfare, 1974-1993, (3 folders) (Box 191)
  - Seals, 1971-1991 (Box 191)
  - Seals, 1971-1991 (Box 192)
  - "Semantic confusion"; Word play, 1974-1998 (Box 192)
  - Shannon, Julie, 1990-1996 (Box 192)
  - Sheep and goats, 1962-1995, (2 folders) (Box 192)
  - Shelters, sanctuaries, and refuges, 1971-1999, (3 folders) (Box 192)
  - Shelters, sanctuaries, and refuges, 1971-1999 (Box 193)
  - Shenandoah County, Va., animal shelter, 1986-1997, undated, (3 folders) (Box 193)
  - Shopping malls, 1978 (Box 193)
  - Silver Spring, Md., research monkey case; Taub, Edward, 1980-1986, (3 folders) (Box 193)
  - Silver Spring, Md., research monkey case; Taub, Edward, 1980-1986, (2 folders) (Box 194)
  - Skewes, Jeanne R., 1948 (Box 194)
  - Snakes, 1958-1971 (Box 194)
  - Snow geese and water fowl, 1973-1978 (Box 194)
  - Social etiquette, 1929-1937 (Box 194)
  - Society for Animal Protective Legislation, 1957-1999, (3 folders) (Box 194)
  - Society for Animal Protective Legislation, 1957-1999 (Box 195)
  - Society for the Study of Ethics and Animals, 1979-1981 (Box 195)
  - Society of Woman Geographers (Box 195)
    - Articles about Free, 1981-2002 (Box 195)
    - Correspondence, 1982-2001, (2 folders) (Box 195)
    - Fiftieth anniversary of the end of World War II, 1995 (Box 195)
    - Membership, 1967, 1981-1995, (3 folders) (Box 195)
    - Miscellany, 1964-1966, 1975-2000, undated, (4 folders) (Box 196)
    - Newsletter of the Society of Woman Geographers, 1982-2003 (Box 196)
  - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance, 1991-1993 (Box 197)
  - Spira, Henry, 1978-1981, 1991 (Box 197)
  - "State and Anmial Welfare Laws," 1970 (Box 197)
  - Stephenson, Malvina, 1942-1945, 1982, 1991-1996 (Box 197)
  - Stevens, Christine, 1958, 1970-2003, (2 folders) (Box 197)
  - Stevens, Christine, undated, (2 folders) (Box 198)
  - Stevens, Christine and Roger, 1952-1969 (Box 198)
  - Stewart, Rhea Talley, 1962-2002 (Box 198)
  - Tail Waggers' Club, Washington, D.C., 1960-1968 (Box 198)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1970-1977 (Box 198)
  - Thurston, Ethel; American Fund for Alternatives to Animal Research, 1989-1993 (Box 198)
  - Tibet; Bstan-ʼdzin-rgya-mtsho, Dalai Lama XIV, 1954-1979 (Box 198)
  - Tibet, newspaper, 1929, 1947, 2010 (Box 199)
  - Tigers and big cats, 1959-1999 (Box 199)
  - Trans-Species Unlimited, 1981-1988 (Box 199)
  - Truman, Bess Wallace, and Harry S. Truman, 1945, 1993-1994, 2006 (Box 199)
  - Turkistan, Kazakhstan, 1952, undated (Box 199)
  - Turtles and marine animals, 1955-1992 (Box 199)
  - "Two down and one to go," War Department pamphlet no. 21-31, 1945 (Box 199)
  - United Action for Animals, 1967-1992, (2 folders) (Box 199)
  - United Nations, 1946, 1953, 1968, 1976 (Box 199)
  - United States Postal Service inauguration, 1971, July 1 (Box 199)
  - United States stereotypes in the Soviet Union, circa 1950 (Box CL 1)
  - Universities Federation for Animal Welfare, 1958-1978 (Box 199)
  - Universities Federation for Animal Welfare, 1958-1978 (Box 200)
  - University Against War, 1937, Apr. (Box 200)
  - Veal and calves, 1969-1980, (2 folders) (Box 200)
  - Veganism, 1974, 2001-2002 (Box 200)
  - Vegetarian Society of the District of Columbia, 1975-1986, 1997-2001 (Box 200)
  - Vegetarianism, 1956-2000 (Box 200)
  - Vegetarianism, 1956-2000, (7 folders) (Box 201)
  - Vegetarianism, 1956-2000 (Box 202)
  - Veterinary medicine, 1957-1990, (3 folders) (Box 202)
  - Vieques Island, Puerto Rico (Box 202)
    - Animal cruelty, 1985-1988 (Box 202)
    - Animal shelter, 1986-1988 (Box 202)
    - Articles and writings by Free, 1987-1994 (Box 202)
    - "A Call for Help," 1985-1990 (Box 202)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1994, 2004 (Box 202)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1994, 2004, (2 folders) (Box 203)
    - Euthanasia, 1981-1987 (Box 203)
    - Federación Protectora de Animales de Puerto Rico, 1983-1987 (Box 203)
    - Funding, Vieques Animal Emergency Fund, 1987-1994 (Box 203)
    - History and conservation, 1986-1988 (Box 203)
    - Horses, 1987-1990 (Box 203)
    - Hunter, Sally, 1990-1995 (Box 203)
    - Hurricane Hugo (1989), 1989-1996 (Box 203)
    - Military concerns, 1978, 1986-1989 (Box 203)
    - Miscellany, 1983-2006, (2 folders) (Box 204)
    - Mitchell, Chris, 1987-1996 (Box 204)
    - Paladin's Veterinary Welfare, 1987-1991 (Box 204)
    - Photographs, 1963, 1977, 1983-1997, (3 folders) (Box 204)
    - Photographs, circa 1990-circa 1994, (3 folders) (Box 205)
    - Travel, 1984-1993 (Box 205)
    - Vieques Humane Society, 1987-2003, (2 folders) (Box 205)
    - Vieques Times, 1987, 1994-2003 (Box 205)
    - Vieques Times, 1987, 1994-2003, (3 folders) (Box 206)
  - Virginia (film), 1939-1940, 1994 See also OV 2, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 206)
  - Virginia (state), 1904-2004 (Box 206)
  - Virginia (state), 1904-2004, (3 folders) (Box 207)
  - Virginia Federation of Humane Societies, 1959-1996, (3 folders) (Box 207)
  - Virginia Native Plant Society, 1989-1991 (Box 208)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va., 1980-1982 (Box 208)
  - Vivisection, 1954-2002, (4 folders) (Box 208)
  - Voice of the Voiceless, 1970-1974 (Box 208)
  - Walker, Ernest P., 1913-1964, (4 folders) (Box 209)
  - Washington Animal Rescue League, Washington, D.C., 1953-1999, (3 folders) (Box 210)
  - Washington Humane Society, Washington, D.C., 1933-1996, (4 folders) (Box 210)
  - Washington Humane Society, Washington, D.C., 1933-1996, (3 folders) (Box 211)
  - Washington Independent Writers, directory, 1977 (Box 211)
  - Washington National Cathedral, Washington, D.C., 1990-1991 (Box 211)
  - Washington Press Club, Washington, D.C., 1931-2001 See also OV 6, same heading; See also Container 154, National Press Club, (2 folders) (Box 211)
  - Washington Press Club, Washington, D.C., 1931-2001 See also Container 154, National Press Club, (7 folders) (Box 212)
  - Washington Press Club, Washington, D.C., 1931-2001 See also Container 154, National Press Club, (3 folders) (Box 213)
  - Weber, Shirley; Network for Ani-males and Females, 1989-1990 (Box 214)
  - Westmoreland Hills, Bethesda, Md., 1970-1982, 1997, (2 folders) (Box 214)
  - Wetlands, 1959-1990, (2 folders) (Box 214)
  - Whales and dolphins, 1962-2005, (3 folders) (Box 214)
  - Whales and dolphins, 1962-2005, (4 folders) (Box 215)
  - White House events and press releases, 1943-1982 (Box 215)
  - Whitehurst, William, 1970-1973 (Box 215)
  - Whittell, George, will, 1969-1974 (Box 216)
  - Wildlife (Box 216)
    - Defenders of Wildlife, 1955-1971, 1989-1993 (Box 216)
    - Department of the Interior, 1963-1995, (2 folders) (Box 216)
    - Miscellany, 1951-1997, (2 folders) (Box 216)
    - Miscellany, 1951-1997, (5 folders) (Box 217)
    - National Wildlife Federation, 1959-1981 (Box 217)
    - "Plenipotentiary Conference to Conclude an International Convention on Trade in Certain Species of Wildlife," Washington, D.C., 1973 (Box 217)
    - Refuges, 1947-1994 (Box 217)
    - Refuges, 1947-1994, (2 folders) (Box 218)
    - World Wildlife Fund, 1963-1996 (Box 218)
  - Wolfe, Thomas, 1935-1936, 1980 (Box 218)
  - Wolves and coyotes, 1973-1982 (Box 218)
  - Women (Box 218)
    - African American women, 1943-2000, (2 folders) (Box 218)
    - General, 1933-2004 (Box 218)
    - General, 1933-2004, (2 folders) (Box 219)
    - Journalists; "News women," 1937-2000, (2 folders) (Box 219)
  - Wooten, Paul, 1946-1953 (Box 219)
  - Working for Animals used in Research, Drugs, and Surgery (WARDS), 1959-2000, (2 folders) (Box 219)
  - Working for Animals used in Research, Drugs, and Surgery (WARDS), 1959-2000, (2 folders) (Box 220)
  - World Society for the Protection of Animals, 1960-2000, (4 folders) (Box 220)
  - World Society for the Protection of Animals, 1960-2000, (4 folders) (Box 221)
  - Worms, 1976-1995 (Box 221)
  - Wright, Phyllis, 1941, 1988-1990 (Box 221)
  - Zoos, 1919-2000, (3 folders) (Box 221)
  - Zoos, 1919-2000, (6 folders) (Box 222)
  - Zoos, 1919-2000, (4 folders) (Box 223)
- Photographs, 1920-2015 (Box 223-237)
  The Photographs series comprises prints, negatives, and scrapbooks that mostly document Free, her family, her friends, and travels in the late 1940s. The photographs represent a mix of professional portraits and snapshots. The travel photographs are extensive and document Free’s travels with Verna Mae Feuerhelm Cody in 1946 and 1947 throughout Asia, Europe, and the Middle East. Of note from this trip are many photographs from India taken around the time the Indian Independence Act went into effect in 1947. A detailed itinerary of this trip can be found in the "Around the world with Ann and Verna" file in the Subject File series. Other photographs documenting Free’s travels include those related to her position with the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration in China and work in Europe reporting on the Marshall Plan. The oral history photographs include noteworthy images handpicked by the donor to accompany transcripts found in the Personal File series. Researchers should be aware that photographs exist in other series within the collection and were retained within those files to maintain appropriate context.
  Material types include prints, negatives, and scrapbooks.
  - Carson, Rachel, related photographs, 1970-1994, (2 folders) (Box 223)
  - Carson, Rachel, related photographs, 1970-1994 (Box 224)
  - China; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), circa 1940-1947, (5 folders) (Box 224)
  - China; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1946-1947, (5 folders) (Box 225)
  - China; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1946-1947, 2015 See also OV 4, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 226)
  - Film stars and celebrities, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 226)
  - Free, Ann Cottrell (Box 226)
    - Chronological, circa 1930s-circa 1940s, (2 folders) (Box 226)
    - Chronological, circa 1940s-circa 1980s, (5 folders) (Box 227)
    - Chronological, circa 1990s-2002, undated, (4 folders) (Box 228)
    - Death, 2005 (Box 228)
    - Notable places and locations, circa 1920s-circa 1980s (Box 228)
    - Studio portraits, circa 1930s-circa 1990s (Box 229)
    - With First Ladies of the United States, 1989-1995 (Box 229)
    - With James Free, circa 1950s-circa 1990s (Box 229)
    - Youth and childhood, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 229)
  - Friends and family (Box 229)
    - Blake, George, circa 1934 (Box 229)
    - Cottrell, Emily Blake (mother), circa 1920s-circa 1970s (Box 229)
    - Free, James (husband), circa 1920s-circa 1990s (Box 229)
    - Free, James (husband), circa 1920s-circa 1990s (Box 230)
    - Johnson, Margaret L., 1932-1939, 1959-1960, undated (Box 230)
    - Miscellaneous friends and family, circa 1920s-circa 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 230)
    - Miscellaneous friends and family, circa 1920s-circa 1990s, (2 folders) (Box 231)
    - Oudine, John, circa 1938, undated (Box 231)
    - Scrapbook, circa 1920s-circa 1930s, undated (Box 231)
  - Harding, Warren G., New York Herald Tribune dedication, circa 1922 See OV 4, same heading (Box OV 4)
  - Marshall Plan, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 232)
  - "'News women' and war," 1942-1944 (Box 232)
  - Oral history photographs, circa 1930s-circa 1990s (Box 232)
  - Oral history photographs, circa 1930s-circa 1990s (Box 233)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, related photographs, 1948-1989, undated, (4 folders) (Box 233)
  - Travel (Box 233)
    - "Around the world with Ann and Verna," circa 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 233)
    - "Around the world with Ann and Verna," 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 234)
    - "Around the World: Women and Children," circa 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 234)
    - Asia, 1946-1947 (Box 234)
    - Austria, 1949 (Box 234)
    - Burma, 1947 (Box 234)
    - Dead Sea, 1947 (Box 234)
    - Egypt, 1947 (Box 234)
    - England, 1948 (Box 234)
    - Europe, circa 1947-circa 1948 (Box 234)
    - Europe, circa 1947-circa 1949, (3 folders) (Box 235)
    - France, 1948 (Box 235)
    - Germany, 1947 (Box 235)
    - Greece, 1947 (Box 235)
    - Hong Kong, 1947 (Box 235)
    - India, 1947, (2 folders) (Box 235)
    - India, 1947, (4 folders) (Box 236)
    - Italy, 1947 (Box 236)
    - Ladākh, India; "Little Tibet," 1947 (Box 236)
    - Malaysia; Singapore, 1947 (Box 236)
    - Pakistan; Punjab region, 1947 (Box 236)
    - Palestine; Jerusalem, 1947 (Box 236)
    - Red Sea, 1947 (Box 236)
    - Ship voyage, Empire Joy, 1946 (Box 236)
    - Ship voyage, Queen Elizabeth, 1947 (Box 236)
    - South China Sea, 1947 (Box 236)
    - Spain; Portugal, 1974, 1985, undated (Box 237)
    - Suez Canal, 1947 (Box 237)
    - Thailand, 1947 (Box 237)
    - Unidentified, circa 1946-circa 1948 (Box 237)
    - Vietnam, 1947 (Box 237)
    - Yemen, 1947 (Box 237)
- Notebooks and Diaries, 1933-2004 (Box 237-289)
  This series contains Free’s notebooks and diaries spanning from the early 1930s until her death in 2004. Some notebooks are labeled according to topic, but most are chronological, documenting both professional and personal aspects of her life. In most cases, there is little distinction between the personal and professional, with many notebooks featuring notes on articles, drafts, interviews, and research as well as more domestic matters including appointments, grocery shopping, and house maintenance. Noteworthy diaries include those reflecting her time in China, India, and Europe in the 1940s. Also of note are notebooks related to Rachel Carson and a group of notebooks surrounding the birth of her daughter, Elissa Blake Free, in 1955.